Hi, on behalf of Expert Villlage.com I'm Shelly here at AA Callister in Salt Lake City, Utah.
Today we are talking about how to purchase a winter horse blanket.
One of the things you want to consider on a winter horse blanket is the insulation value.
Each blanket is going to have its own insulation value and that?s what keeps the horse warm.
So you're going to choose something that is measured in ounces or grams.
It will state on the blanket what it is.
So many ounces or so many grams.
Say for instance, 8 ounces is about equivalent to 220 grams of insulation.
Just so you have something to compare against.
That's what?s going to keep your horse warm.
Now you're going to need more insulation if you have a colder barn or if your horse is turned out and less insulation if you horse is in a warm barn.
Or maybe if your horse has been body clipped you're going to need something that has more insulation value.
Whereas if you don't care if he has a longer coat you can have something with less insulation value.
Also you're want to keep that mind when you're choosing a blanket because a blanket in the spring and the fall doesn't need to have quite as much insulation as one you're going to use in the winter because that's what?s going to keep your horse warm.
That's what?s in the middle of the blanket.
So the insulation value is what you are going to want to consider when you choose a winter horse blanket.